<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network and Module Analysis on Gene list mining</title>
    <link>/network-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network and Module Analysis on Gene list mining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/network-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gene regulatory network analysis</title>
      <link>/network-analysis/gene_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network-analysis/gene_network/</guid>
      <description>2.1.1 STRING 2.1.2 IMEx 2.1.3 IntAct 2.1.4 DIP 2.1.5 BioGRID 2.1.6 MINT 2.1.7 InnateDB 2.1.8 HuRI 2.1.9 InWeb 2.1.10 NDEx 2.1.11 IID 2.1.12 SIGNOR 2.1.13 MatrixDB 2.1.14 I2D 2.1.15 SPIKE Breaking:
2.1.1 STRING Introduction: STRING is a database of known and predicted protein-protein interactions. The interactions include direct (physical) and indirect (functional) associations; they stem from computational prediction, from knowledge transfer between organisms, and from interactions aggregated from other (primary) databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TF gene interaction database</title>
      <link>/network-analysis/tf_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network-analysis/tf_regulation/</guid>
      <description>2.2.1 JASPAR 2.2.2 AnimalTFDB 2.2.3 CHEA 2.2.4 RegNetwork Breaking:
2.2.1 JASPAR Introduction: JASPAR is a regularly maintained open-access database storing manually curated transcription factors (TF) binding profiles as position frequency matrices (PFMs). PFMs summarize occurrences of each nucleotide at each position in a set of observed TF-DNA interactions. PFMs can be transformed to probabilistic or energistic models to construct position weight matrices (PWMs) or position-specific scoring matrices (PSSMs), which can be used to scan any DNA sequence to predict TF binding sites (TFBSs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-gene interaction database</title>
      <link>/network-analysis/mirna_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network-analysis/mirna_regulation/</guid>
      <description>2.3.1 TargetScan 2.3.2 miRBase 2.3.3 miRDB 2.3.4 RNAhybrid 2.3.5 miRTarbase 2.3.6 miR2Disease 2.3.7 TarBase 2.3.8 mirDIP Breaking:
2.3.1 TargetScan Introduction: TargetScan predicts biological targets of miRNAs by searching for the presence of conserved 8mer, 7mer, and 6mer sites that match the seed region of each miRNA (Lewis et al., 2005). As options, predictions with only poorly conserved sites and predictions with nonconserved miRNAs are also provided. Also identified are sites with mismatches in the seed region that are compensated by conserved 3’ pairing (Friedman et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ceRNA-gene interaction database</title>
      <link>/network-analysis/cerna_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network-analysis/cerna_regulation/</guid>
      <description>2.4.1 ENCODE 2.4.2 starBase 2.4.3 miRcode 2.4.4 DIANA-LncBase 2.4.5 OmniPath 2.4.6 ceRDB 2.4.7 LncACTdb 2.4.8 PceRBase Breaking:
2.4.1 ENCODE Introduction: The ENCODE Portal, developed and maintained by the Data Coordination Center (ENCODE DCC), is the canonical source for all experimental metadata and data from ENCODE and associated projects. The ENCODE Portal contains raw and ground-level analysis data generated by participating mapping centers using a wide-range of assays (integrative analysis data are available at the SCREEN portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and Visualization Tools</title>
      <link>/network-analysis/analysis_visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network-analysis/analysis_visualization/</guid>
      <description>2.5.1 GeneMANIA 2.5.2 NetworkAnalyst 2.5.3 ConsensusPathDB 2.5.4 iRegulon 2.5.5 NAViGaTOR 2.5.6 FunCoup 2.5.7 miRTargetLink 2.5.8 FFLtool Breaking:
2.5.1 GeneMANIA Introduction: GeneMANIA finds other genes that are related to a set of input genes, using a very large set of functional association data. Association data include protein and genetic interactions, pathways, co-expression, co-localization and protein domain similarity.
Data Source Statistics
Type Number species 9 Data sources 22 Network 7 Installation:The GeneMANIA app offers a cytoscape command for scripting purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
